Cameron H. Matthews

1046 Via Vera Cruz San Marcos, CA 92078

(confidential)

Phone: (619)384-8520

9a-9p PT cameronhmatthews@yahoo.com

Summary

Technology executive with strong leadership ability, successful management skills, and proven organizational capabilities who possesses over 30 years of cross-vertical security, software, and systems engineering experience. Security and technology pioneer in the areas of threat intelligence exchange, rapid vulnerability notification, and Electronic Health Records (EHR). Areas of expertise include:

- Business security strategy
- Risk and threat management
- Team building and leadership
- Secure software and systems engineering
- Systems integration

Professional Experience

Sentek Global San Diego, CA Dec 2006 - Present Chief Security Officer Chief Technology Officer Vice President

- Instrumental in expanding company into a local technology and security powerhouse; growth from 11 employees to 144; \$4M annual revenue to \$37M
- Created Commercial Division: penetration testing, vulnerability assessments, IR/forensics, risk management, secure architecture/SSDLC program, outsourced CSO. Created and trained 5 penetration testing teams: Network, Web Application, Wireless, Social Engineering, and Critical Infrastructure (powergrid, SCADA).
- Instructor for UCSD Rady Business School, training CEO/CIOs by translating security concepts and current issues into business-relevant solutions.
- Leading Navy programs through cloud security and acquisition wickets to transition to cloud infrastructure.
- Won ~\$450M in contracts including Computer Network Attack and Defense, security engineering, SOA engineering services, and risk assessments of all U.S. Navy networks, systems, and applications.
- Provided software, compliance, and security engineering services including threat modeling and remediation for classified Navy/Army Chemical/Biological/Radiological/Nuclear system and classified Navy/Coast Guard intelligence system.
- Managed two teams of 30 security engineers providing security compliance and engineering services to the Navy through DIACAP and RMF. Security SME for cloud computing, SOA, virtualization, and cryptography. Wrote Navy-wide cybersecurity governance.
- Wrote all corporate security policies and corporate security plan, incident response plan, DR/BCP, organizational threat model, and IT AUP.
- Created security/IT lab for IT patch testing, security training, and prototyping.
- Built dynamic security awareness smartphone application for the DHS.
- Built prototypes for next-generation military Command and Control systems and cross-platform mobile applications.

 Conducted international business development (Europe, Africa, Southeast Asia) for C4I engineering products and services.

Layered Intelligence Corporation

Sep 2004 - Dec 2006

San Francisco, CA

Chief Technology Officer

Project: Millivox.Net

Developed e-Commerce and collaboration website for the sales and secure distribution of digital content

Project: Data Driven Software Corporation (d2sc.com)

Created technology revitalization plan, risk mitigation strategies, enterprise architecture standards, security policy, and engineering procedures

Project: Layered Global Services

- Developed and ran the division performing managed technology offshoring.
- Managed software engineering teams around the world including the U.S., the Ukraine, Mexico, Russia, England, and Argentina.

UFO Communications

Nov 2000 - Aug 2004

San Francisco, CA

VP of Software Engineering

- Built the Operations Support System (OSS) that automated the business processes of the telecommunications enterprise
- Managed the software engineering team that delivered seven releases of the OSS over four years, all on-schedule and dramatically under budget
- Worked with corporate attorneys to patent OSS processes and algorithms
- Managed tech due diligence enabling sale to Cogent Communications

Shippers Network

Nov 1999 - Sep 2000

Carlsbad, CA

Chief Technology Officer

Built secure B2B Transportation Exchange and transport management system

eHNC (now Fair Isaac Corporation/FICO)

Jun 1999 – Nov 1999

San Diego, CA

Lead Software Engineer

 Architected enterprise data integration standard; designed and implemented custom security authentication protocol

Science Applications International Corporation / Global Integrity / **Tenth Mountain Systems**

Dec 1996 - Jun 1999

San Diego, CA

Senior Staff Security Engineer

 Architected, built, and demonstrated the world's first and only anonymous, authenticated security vulnerability, incident, and risk clearinghouse for the U.S. financial services sector (in conjunction with the U.S. Department of the Treasury). This system, called the Financial Services Information Sharing and Analysis Center (FS-ISAC), recently won the award for Excellence in Information Security at the 2013 RSA Conference. www.fsisac.com

- Pioneered the first security vulnerability advisory system (REACT Reflector) used to notify customers of security vulnerabilities based upon hardware, software, and architecture profiles
- Designed and built a host- and network-based security surveillance system (spyware) which detected and audited usage of certain key media types and reported the activity to remote servers
- Core developer in the Secure Electronic Transactions (SET) e-commerce protocol compliance suite
- Performed security and system architecture reviews for global financial institutions including some of the largest banks and trading floors in the U.S.

O'Reilly and Associates	Apr 1996 - Dec 1996
	· •
Sebastopol, CA	Software Developer, WebSite
	Development Team

Maintained security and website production products

Science Applications International	Jul 1995 – Jun 1996
Corporation San Diego, CA	Consulting Software Engineer,
3 ,	PacMedNet Project

 Pioneered a \$38M global Electronic Health Record system that allowed medical treatment facilities to locate and securely exchange digital medical records and images world-wide

Integrated Computer Management	Feb 1995 - Jul 1995
Solutions	
Dallas, TX	Principal / Consultant

- Authored medical informatics software for a national hospital group
- Created an expert system for a telecommunications company

Science Applications International	Feb 1988 - Feb 1995
Corporation	
San Diego, CA	

- System architect for one of the world's largest medical informatics systems;
 \$1.6 billion DoD healthcare project for Military Treatment Facilities worldwide
- Held various engineering and management positions throughout my tenure

Digital Equipment Corporation	Jul 1985 - Feb 1988
San Diego, CA	Consulting Systems Manager,
	Software Group

Bit-7 Computer Systems	Aug 1982 – Jul 1985
San Diego, CA	Contract Programmer

Training and Certifications

 Certified Information Systems Security Professional (CISSP), (ISC)2 License 372792

- Certificate of Cloud Security Knowledge (CCSK), CSA, Code 400627370396
- Amazon Solution Architect training
- RSA and Cloud Security Alliance Conference 2012, 2013, 2014
- BlackHat and DEFCON 2011, 2012, 2013, 2014, 2015
- BlackHat Incident Response (Mandiant) training
- BlackHat Advanced WiFi Penetration Testing training
- BlackHat Maltego (Social Engineering, Open Source Intelligence) training
- BlackHat Exploit Laboratory training (Vulnerability exploit creation)
- BlackHat Samurai Web Testing Framework training (web app pentesting)
- "Attacking, Defending, and Building SCADA Systems" training, BlackHat 2014
- "Assessing and Exploiting Industrial Control Systems with SamuraiSTFU" training, BlackHat 2013
- Financing Strategy: Sources of Capital and Business Plans, UCSD Extension, March, 2015
- Agile Scrum Training, CollabNet
- Department of Defense Architecture Framework (DODAF) training
- Sitecore Certified Developer (.NET-based Content Management System; ASP.NET/C# and XSLT)
- VMWare vSphere/vCenter training

Speaking Engagements, Publications, Whitepapers, Recognition

- Speaker (Sentek, Barney&Barney, ESET), Preparing for the Inevitable: Best Practices to Protect Your Company from a Data Breach. June, 2015.
- Speaker (San Diego Women in Finance), Cybersecurity Impact to the Bottom Line, October, 2014.
- WiFi Security Standard. San Diego Cyber Center of Excellence. April 2015.
- Panelist, "Information as Warfare", AFCEA C4ISR Conference, April 2013.
- Military looking to DISA for clear direction on security in the cloud. Defense Systems Magazine. September 2012.
- SENTEK HIGH TECH DEFENSE BOOSTS ECONOMY. KNSD-TV Channel 7/39 broadcast. April 2010.
- Corporations should follow government's lead on attribution of cyber attacks. *The Daily Transcript*. February 2010.
- Don't forget who's behind a cyberattack. *Washington Technology*. February 2010.
- Local Arena Plays Large Role in Protecting Against Enemy Cyber Attacks. San Diego Business Journal. February 2010.
- Cloud computing has uncertainties, is moving forward. *The Daily Transcript*. October 2009.
- Governance, guidance necessary in the cloud. San Diego Daily Transcript. October 2009.
- Defining AFRICOM's mission. Signal Online (an AFCEA publication).
 December 2008.
- Bridging the SOA divide for deployed assets. *Defense Update*. *Defense Systems*. September 2008.
- Supporting the National Anti-terrorism Initiative in the Philippines. Whitepaper; May 2008.
- 2008/2009/2010/2011/2012/2013 San Diego Business Journal's Technology Executive of the Year finalist
- 2011/2012/2015 San Diego Magazine's Top Tech Exec Awards finalist

References and Education

Available on request